上周今夜秀 - Trump & 选举结果  （时间轴/不想校对/翻译/压制 by Pepita_貘饕_，禁止转载）
LAST WEEK TONIGHT - Trump & Election Results
嗨，你好 欢迎参加演出，
Hi there. Welcome to the show,
仍然从这个空白中走过来
still coming to you from this blank void,
我不认为这是炼狱，但又没有证据
which I don't think is purgatory, but I can't prove otherwise.
我们将直接开始这个星期的主要故事
And we're gonna jump straight in with our main story this week,
不幸的是，连续第二周，
which unfortunately, for the second week in a row,
这期是关于我们刚刚举行的选举，请相信我，
concerns the election we just had, and believe me,
我对此跟你一样感到失望
I'm just as disappointed as you about that.
我宁愿今晚度过
I would much rather spend tonight
谈论在西孟加拉邦发现的这种稀有海龟
talking about this rare turtle found in West Bengal.
看看它有多黄！
Look how yellow it is!
看来他遇到了一点来自乌龟黑手党的麻烦
It looks like he got into some trouble with the turtle mafia
正试图装成一个花生MM豆
while trying to disguise itself as a peanut M&M.
它看起来像一个参加了化妆舞会
It looks like it went to a costume party
打扮成了鸡蛋中比较不健康的那个部分
dressed as the less healthy part of the egg.
据专家...
According to experts...
乌龟的这种稀有颜色，归因于缺乏被称为酪氨酸的色素
The rare color of the turtle is attributed to the deficiency of pigment called tyrosine
但是我觉得，你可以继续，把那个装得跟真的一样的东西
But according to me, you can go ahead and drop that little factoid
放在那个标为《谁tmd在乎》的文件夹里
in a file labeled "Who gives a shit?"
你看看，那乌龟真tmd黄！
Because look how fucking yellow that turtle is!
我整个节目都可以一直继续讨论这个闪亮的,cheddar芝士般的错误
We could've done this whole show about this shiny, cheddar cheese mistake,
但是，我们必须谈论这个混蛋, 因为在平时
but instead, we have to talk about this asshole, because in normal times,
总统选举的失败者会承认他们输了，
the loser of a presidential election would simply acknowledge that they lost,
然后这个国家将继续前进
and the country would get to move on.
但截至周六的录制，举行选举后整整一周，
But as of our taping on Saturday, a full week after the election was called,
Trump 仍拒绝承认竞选失败
Trump is still refusing to concede.
虽然这不足为奇的是，
And while that is not remotely surprising,
像下面这样如便一样让人失望的事实发生着：
what has been disappointing has been shit like this.
国务卿 Mike Pompeo 引起了强烈震动
Secretary of State Mike Pompeo sent shockwaves
当他似乎驳回选举结果时
when he appeared to dismiss the election results.
我们将会平稳过渡到第二届 Trump 政府
There will be a smooth transition to a second Trump administration.
好咩，我们都准备好了
All right. We're ready.
你在tmd说什么，你这个职业鬼脸？
What the fuck are you talking about, you business Grimace?
你是国务卿，你应该强行谴责政变
You're the Secretary of State.You're supposed to forcefully denounce coups
并且当 CIA 在中美洲或南美洲策划了一个政变的时候睁一只眼闭一只眼
and look the other way if the CIA does one in Central or South America.
这就是你的全部工作了
That is literally your whole job.
尽管有些人认为 Pompeo 是在那儿开玩笑，
And while some have suggested that Pompeo was joking there,
他也没有承认拜登当选总统这件事
he also hasn't yet acknowledged that Biden is president-elect
大多数共和党人也没有
nor have most Republicans.
Mitch McConnell 不仅声称 Trump 100％
Mitch McConnell not only claimed Trump is 100 percent
有权挑战选举结果，
within his rights to challenge the election results,
他是这样讲的：
he went on to say this.
我们不要指指点点了，不要再说总统
Let's not have any lectures, no lectures about how the president
应该立即欣然接受初步选举结果
should immediately, cheerfully accept preliminary election results
而正是这些人，在过去的四年中
from the same characters who just spent four years
拒绝接受上次选举的有效性
refusing to accept the validity of the last election.
Ok, 首先，没有人期望 Trump 立即高高兴兴地接受结果
Okay. First, no one expected Trump to immediately,cheerfully accept the results.
他无力接受任何事情
He's incapable of cheerfully accepting anything
除了**，支持纳粹，
apart from blowjobs, Nazi endorsements,
和在一个陌生卡车里尖叫的机会
and the opportunity to scream inside a stranger's truck.
那是谁的卡车？
Whose truck is that?
我告诉你谁绝对不在乎，这老几
I tell you who definitely doesn't care. This guy.
现在是他的卡车了，叭！叭！
It's his truck now. Honk! Honk!
其次，虽然2016年有一些左派人士
And second, while there were some on the left in 2016
敦促与结果抗争，
who urged fighting the results,
希拉里在选举第二天就正式承认竞选失败
Hillary formally conceded the day after the election,
奥巴马在之后第二天就在白宫有接见了 Trump
and Obama had Trump in the White House the day after that.
第二天 然而，共和党人试图为他们支持
And yet, Republicans are trying to defend their support
Trump 站不住脚的行为进行辩解
for Trump's indefensible behavior
一位高级官员说对此说到
with one senior official saying...
就多再迁就他几天能怎么样嘛
what is the downside for humorning him for this littl bit of time?
一个永远无法得到很好解决的问题，不管问这个的人
A question that never ends well, whether the ones asking it
是过度劳累需要休息一下的父母，还是是魏玛共和国的人
are overworked parents who need a break or the Weimar Republic.
所以今晚，让我们一起看看
So tonight, let's look at just
Trump 推翻这次选举的案子是有多弱
how weak Trump's case for overturning this election is
以及迁就他会带来哪些真正的危害
and what real harm humoring him will do.
让我们从案例本身开始
And let's start with the case itself
因为现在有很多指控和诉讼飞来飞去
because there are lots of accusations and lawsuits flying around right now,
如果你是随机翻到右翼媒体的观众，你可能会认为，
and if you are a casual viewer of right-wing media, you might think,
“嗯，这里一定有点猫腻
"Well, there must be something here.
不然他们不会没目的地自找麻烦，浪费精力”
They wouldn't be going to all this trouble over nothing."
但是事实是他们就是在浪费精力。这里面还真的没什么可以做文章的。
But the thing is they are. This really is nothing.
让我们从经常宣称的逝世的人在投票这件事情说起吧
And let's start with the frequently made claim about dead voters.
如果你叔叔是如噩梦般讨厌，然后你们在 Facebook 上依然互相关注
If your uncle is a nightmare and you're still friends on Facebook,
那你可能已经看过这个帖子，它声称有一个清单
you might have seen this post claiming there a list
在 Michigan 州有14,000名逝世的人投了票
of 14,000 dead people who voted in Michigan,
但是当CNN挑选出50个名字进行抽查时，
but when CNN picked out 50 of the names to do a spot check,
他们发现其中37人已经死亡，没有投票
they discovered 37 were dead and hadn't casted votes
其中5人投票了但是还活着，以及8人活着但是没有投票
5 had voted but still alive, and 8 alive but hadn't voted.
这意味着投票的死者为零
Meaning exactly zero were dead people who voted.
是的，那只是一个抽样的例子，但是你如果在奥利奥饼干工厂
And yes, that is just a sample, but you are at an Oreo factory
你从生产线上50个奥利奥里挑选的50个奥利奥
and 50 out of 50 Oreos you picked off the line
全都是压扁的两只老鼠中间夹着用过的安全套（🤮）
were just two rats squished around a used condom,
你可能不会冒险相信下一个来到你面前的饼干
you might well not risk trusting the next cookie that comes past you.
死人投票的主张也由 Tucker Carlson （Fox Nexws 主持人，被诉性骚扰）提出的
The claim of dead people voting was also advanced by Tucker Carlson,
一个刚刚输惨了的80年代滑雪场地地头蛇
an 80s ski bully who just lost the big race.
他特别大张旗鼓地举了一个例子
And he went in big on one example in particular.
这在某些方面，是一个鼓舞人心的故事：超越死亡的投票之胜
In some ways, it's an inspiring story: the triumph of voting over death.
没有人能比 Georgia州Covington县的 James Blalock 更能充分体现这一故事了
And no one quite embodies that story like James Blalock of Covington, Georgia.
Blalock 先生直到2006年去世前，曾担任邮递员33年
Mr. Blalock was a mailman for 33 years, until he passed away in 2006.
14年后，根据联邦州记录，他仍在邮递东西
14 years later, according to state records, he was still mailing things.
James Blalock 在上周的选举中进行了投票。他是如何做到的呢？
James Blalock cast a ballot in last week's election. How did he do that?
哦，这是一个很好的问题，你这个服务员的噩梦（有关小费的一个评论）
Ooh, that's an excellent question, you waiter's nightmare.
现在，这个观点被其他人抓住，首当其冲传了起来的是
Now, that segment got picked up and circulated by among others,
Matt Gaetz（共和党议员）和 Trump 竞选团队
Matt Gaetz and the Trump campaign itself.
这的确使你想知道那个逝者是如何投票的
And it does make you wonder how did that dead man vote.
也许他的遗孀可以回答这一点
Maybe his widow has an answer.
他没有投票
He didn't vote.
-是你投的      -对是我投的
-It was you.  -It was me.
Agnes Blalock 以她结婚后的名字投了票，Newton县也确认了这点
Agnes Blalock voted using her married name, Newton County confirmed.
她的选民登记签名是 James E. Blalock, Jr. 夫人
Her voter registration was signed as Mrs. James E. Blalock, Jr.,
这也是她投票时使用的签名
and that's exactly how she signed her name when she voted
在11月3日的大选中
in the November 3rd  general election.
你为谁投票？你不一定要告诉我们。
Who did you vote for? You don't have to share that.
在美国，选谁是一个非常私人的问题，大家最好不要随便问别人
我投票给了民主党，选了 Biden
I voted for the Democrats. For Biden.
在美国，选谁是一个非常私人的问题，大家最好不要随便问别人
我懂了
I see.
我想我其实是对另一方投了反对票。
I guess I voted against the other one, really.
好的，所以这个说法是胡说八道。他没有投票，她投的
Okay, so the claim was bullshit. He didn't vote. She did.
顺便说一句，并不是喜欢 Biden 而投的, 而是反对另一边
And by the way, not so much for Biden as against the other one,
意味着这位96岁的老人对于选举的态度
meaning this 96-year-old's approach to the election
就像20岁的进步者一样
was pretty much the same as that of 20-year-old progressives.
我想知道他们还有什么共同点
I wonder what else they have in common.
她是否也有一系列Dank梗的，并且每天花
Does she also have a collection of dank memes and spends
5个小时在Twitter上骂 Bill de Blasio（民主党，前纽约市长）？
five hours a daycalling Bill de Blasio a bitch on Twitter?
我真的希望如此
I really hope so.
然后，有许多来自所谓的吹哨人的声称
Then, there were claims from numerous supposed whistleblowers.
实际上，Lindsey Graham（共和党）, Leslie Jordan（美恐编剧）笔下最糟糕的人物，
In fact, Lindsey Graham, Leslie Jordan's absolute worst character,
给司法​​部发了一封信，要求他们调查一个
sent a letter to the DOJ, asking them to investigate particular claims
由 Pennsylvania 州 Erie 市的一名邮递员主张的指控，他在宣誓口供说
by a postal worker in Erie, Pennsylvania, who said in an affidavit,
他听说了邮寄选票的邮戳时间被人为设置了
that he heard postmarks were being backdated on mail-in ballots
使这些选票看起来像是在选举日收集的
to make it appear as though they'd been collected on Election Day.
但对 Graham 来说，不幸的是，那个人后来撤回了
But unfortunately for Graham, that man later recanted
与调查员谈话时，他口供的那些指控
those claims in his affidavit when talking to investigators.
但是依然坚持他的最初声明
And while is he now insisting that he stands by his initial statements.
真正重要的是要知道
the really important thing to know is
他所在邮局的选票总数，
the total number of ballots from his post office,
他们有着11月3日的邮戳，并在之后送交选举委员会的选票有多少
they were postmarked November 3rd and delivered to the board of elections later.
然而，符合这一标准，潜在的被更改时间的选票总数为2张
So, the maximum number that could've had their date changed was two,
然而，重要的信息来了，这并不是 Joe Biden 赢得了 Pennsylvania 州的决胜票数
which is, and this is true, not the number of votes Joe Biden won Pennsylvania by.
但也许是最奇怪的举报人指控来自内华达州的一名民意调查员
But perhaps the strangest whistleblower accusation involved a poll worker in Nevada
福克斯给了黄金时段来让她陈述她的指控
who Fox gave a primetime slot to make her claims.
我休息时出去散步，大概走了
I went out to go for a walk on my break and I probably had a
45到54米那么远，我走的地方...
150, 175-foot stretch, where I was walking...
哦，对不起，我真的应该提一嘴
Oh, sorry I really should've mentioned
他们通过把她的声音搞得像
they disguised her identity by making her sound like
Megan Mullaly（演员）正在驱魔一样来伪装她的身份
Megan Mullaly undergoing an exorcism.
但我让她继续
But I'll let her continue.
基本上，她声称自己看到 Biden-Harris 竞选小车车
Basically she claims she saw a Biden-Harris campaign van
停在在投票站外，旁边有人正在处理白色信封。继续！
outside the polling place with people handling white envelopes. Go!
当我走近时，看到信封被撕开了
As I got closer, the envelopes were being torn open.
有两个男的或两个人放下信封
There were two men or two people dropping the envelopes.
两个人扯开他们，转身面对小货车
And two people ripping them open and turning and facing the van
并在它们上画什么或标记它们
and drawing on them or marking them.
当我走过时，我看了看，心想：“这些都是选票 ”
And as I walked by, I looked and I go, "those are ballots."
好的，我就直说了
Okay. I'm just gonna say it.
这要么是胡扯，要么是有史以来最愚蠢的计划
That is either total bullshit or the dumbest scheme of all time.
Biden-Harris 竞选团队打开了信封并标记选票
The Biden-Harris campaign opened envelopes and marked ballots
就在光天化日之下的投票站停车场
in the parking lot of a polling place in broad daylight
货车的一面上还有logo
against the side of a van which had their logo on it.
就像在《十一罗汉》中，这些人出现在赌场
That is like if in Oceans 11 they showed up to the casino
开着一辆 logo 是 “Danny Ocean 抢劫服务公司”的大货车
in a giant Danny Ocean's robbery service van,
然后在大厅里慢慢伪装
and slowly put on their disguises in the lobby.
这真是完美的犯罪啊！
It's the perfect crime!
此外，该女子尚未提出正式申诉
Also, that woman hasn't yet filed a formal complaint.
根据 Nevada 总检察管办公室回复，他们收到的只是
According to the Nevada AG's office, all they've received is
编写的宣誓口供，并不包含她的名字，签名和联系信息
redacted affidavit that does not contain her name, signature or contact information.
这意味着他们无法开始正式的调查
Meaning they have no way to begin a proper investigation
而这已经变成了一种模式
and that has been something of a pattern here.
Trump 团队公开宣称存在大范围的欺诈行为，但是
The Trump team making claims of widespread fraud publicly, but there then
这些指控当它们进入法律程序成为记录，就大量地被撤回了
being a huge drop off when it comes to what they're actually filing in court.
在 Michigan 州，他们提起了一项含有234页选举监督员口供的诉讼
In Michigan, they submitted a lawsuit with 234 pages of affidavits from poll watchers,
但是那些真正读过它们的人发现
but those who actually read them found that
他们没有证据表明存在大范围的欺诈行为或严重不当行为
they do not show proof of widespread fraud or egregious misconduct
相反，提出这些指控的人，似乎
Instead, they're either allegations from people who don't seem to
似乎不太了解计票过程如何进行
fully understand how the vote counting process works
所以质疑一些很平常的事情
so are questioning some pretty commonplace things
或者是一些像下面这些一样的狗💩
or they are petty bullshit like, complaining
唱票室内的人们穿着印有“Black Lives Matter”的T恤，或
people insde the counting room wearing "Black Lives Matter" shirts, or
选站工作人员打开投 Donald Trump 的票时翻白眼
the election workers open ballots with Donald Trump votes and rolling their eyes.
两者都不违法啊
Neither of which are illegal.
如果这有帮助的话，让我先提前给未来 Trump 竞选诉讼打个预防针
And if it helps here, let me just head-off any future Trump campaign lawsuits.
选站工作人员吃香蕉不是选民欺诈的证据
A poll worker eating a banana is not evidence of voter fraud.
哼着 Uptown Girl 的副歌不是选民欺诈的证据
One humming the chorus of "Uptown Girl" is not evidence of voter fraud.
现在，戴棒球帽可能是选民欺诈行为的证据
Now, wearing a baseball cap could be evidence of voter fraud,
但前提是佩戴者正在将选票放入碎纸机中
but only if the person wearing it is putting ballot votes into a paper shredder.
如果仅仅是帽子，那也就不是选民欺诈的证据
If it's just the hat part, that again is not evidence of voter fraud.
讲真的，剩下的节目时间我可以一直继续揭穿这些故事
So look, I could spend the rest of this show debunking stories.
问题在于它无边无尽
The problem is it's endless.
最新的指控是投票机或软件更改选票
The latest claim is voting machines or software changed votes
尽管这家政府网络安全机构是由
even though this government cyber security agency created by
Trump 本人签署的一项法案成立的，它发表声明说：
an act that Trump himself signed released a statement saying，
没有任何证据表明任何投票系统会删除或丢了选票，
There is no evidence that any voting system deleted or lost votes,
或变更选票或以任何方式被篡改
changed votes or was in any way compromised。
并说11月3日的选举是美国历史上安保最好的选举
And the Nov. 3rd election was the most secure in American history
实际上，截至本次录制，今年为数不多的看似合理合法
In fact, as of this taping, one of the few seemingly legitimate cases
针对选票欺诈的案子，是这一个
against anyone for voter fraud this year has been this:
Luzerne 县官员表示, 30年来首次
Luzerne County officials say for the first time in 30 years
选民欺诈案被捕，县警官说，
there's been a voter fraud arrest. Country detectives say
Forty Fort 的 Robert Lynn 用他已故母亲的名字
Robert Lynn of Forty Fort signed his deceased mother's name
在缺席选票申请中签名，而这是犯罪
on an absentee ballot application and that's a crime.
Lynn是注册的共和党人
Lynn is a registered Republican.
法院文书显示申请在九月被举报
Court paperwork shows the application flagged in September,
选举官员向县警官报了案
and election officials reported it  to country detectives.
是的，就那一个人，据说是尝试偷一票
Yeah. That's one person allegedly trying to steal one vote
还在九月被标示了，而涉案人员是 Trump 的支持者
that was flagged in September, and the person involved was a Trump supporter.
这不是最重要的事情，最重要的是这发生
And this is not the most important thing, but it happened in
在一个叫做 Forty Fort 的小镇，这真是令人愉悦
a town called Forty Fort, which is just delightful.
现在跟我一起大声说出“Forty Fort”这个词
Just say the words "Forty Fort" out loud right now.
Forty Fort, 在嘴巴上的感觉真是很好
Forty Fort. It feel so good in the mouth.
现在，这个城镇显然是以
Now, apparently the town was named after
最初在那里建堡垒的40位定居者而命名的，
the original 40 settlers who built a fort there,
但我觉得这是胡说八道，因为我拒绝相信
but I call bullshit on that because I refuse to believe
刚好有40个定居者为他们的堡垒命名为
that there just happened to be 40 settlers who named their fort
Forty Fort（四十堡）而没有完全意识到这名字听起来多么有搞笑
Forty Fort without being fully aware of how funny that sounds.
这是我认为事情的经过：他们建造了堡垒，
Here is what I think happened. They built the fort,
一位定居者说，“我们应该怎么称呼这个地方？”
and one settler said, "What should we call this place?"
另一个人说：“谁在乎啊，我们就称它为四十堡好咧”
And another said, "Who cares. Let's just call it Forty Fort."
每个人理所当然地笑得很厉害，并同意就这么叫
And everyone justifiably laughed very hard and agreed to do just that.
然后，另一个没有人喜欢的定居者说：
Then another settler, who no one really liked, said,
“等等！如果有人问我们为什么叫它四十堡咋办？
"Wait! What if someone asks why we called it Forty Fort?
我们不能只是说我们这么喊因为他很搞笑
We can't just say we did it because we thought it was funny."
每个人都悄悄悉悉索索，
And everyone quietly muttered,
“哦，背你妈的时，Ezekiel，你娃真的胎神”
"Oh, my God, Ezekiel. You suck so much,"
所以，然后他们说：“这样吧，如果有人问起的话
So, then they said, "Okay. If anyone asks,
我们就说叫他四十堡时因为我们有40个人
we called it Forty Fort，because there are 40 of us.
虽然我们没有，但是哪个可以说我们作假喃
I mean, there aren't. But who's gonna call us out on that?
反正现在是1770年，大多数人不识字
It's fucking 1770 and most people can't read.
这就是四十堡的得名方式，我会这个故事带进我肉汁之坟
And that is how Forty Fort got its name. I will take that story to my gravy grave.
就公开来讲，我也有足够多的证据来举证
And for the record, I have exactly as much evidence to back that up
共和党在这次选举中普遍存在的选民欺诈行为
as Republicans currently do of widespread voter fraud in this election.
因此，这里的指控完全是胡说八道
So, the allegations here are complete nonsense.
谁都不知道为什么共和党人会以此为乐
And who knows why Republicans are entertaining this.
也许是因为 Georgia 州两个参议院议员席位竞争即将来临
Maybe it's to do with the fact that Georgia has two senate runoffs coming up
他们想让 Trump 开心，，以便可以赢得在此的选票
and they want to keep Trump happy, so it'll help rally voters for them there.
也许他们支持他是因为他们担心
Maybe they're carrying favor with him because they're worried
他将成为未来的权力交易经纪人，我真的不知道
that he'll be a power broker going forward. I don't know.
我所知道的是，针对那个问题
What I do know is that the answer to the question
“迁就他到底有什么危害？”的答案是有很多危害
what is the downside of humoring him is a lot.
因为本届政府拒绝承认选举的结果是
Because this administration's refusal to acknowledge the election's outcome is that
Bide 得不到高级别情报，以及
Biden is not getting high level intelligence reports and
无法获取资金来实现过度
can't access funds meant to facilitate his transition.
然后当然还有这个：
And then of course there is this.
Trump 总统依然拒绝选举失败
President Trump's ongoing  refusal to concede the race
使得 Biden 的新冠计划复杂化
is complicating Biden's pandemic planning.
直到 Trump 政府正式承认 Biden 当选总统，
Until the Trump administration  formally recognizes Biden as president-elect,
卸任的 Trump 官员无法共享关键的新冠疫苗分配计划
outgoing Trump officials can't share critical COVID vaccine distribution plans
与即将到来的拜登队
with the incoming Biden team.
就是这样，这真的很糟糕
Yeah! And that's not great.
随着案件数量以惊人的速度增加，你真的希望新团队
With cases spiking to a terrifying extent, you really want the new team
来应对新冠，以便能够与老团队沟通
handling the pandemic, to be able to talk to the old team.
哪怕，我怀疑旧团队的计划只是一张白板
Even if, as I suspect, the old team's plan was just a single whiteboard
立在 Jared 办公室里，上面什么都没有，除了
in Jared's office with nothing on it except for
找到治愈办法，问好，还画了五个圈圈
"discover cure", question mark, circled five times
然后下面画了一个 Donald Trump，说：“干得真棒，我的新儿子”
and then a drawing of Donald Trump saying "Good job, new son!"
但是纵容 Trump 的伤害还有更多
But the damage of indulging Trump goes even further.
因为它也会带来四面楚歌的 Trump 支持者可怕的幻想
Because it also plays into grim fantasies of embattled Trump supporters.
某种表达地最戏剧性和最愚蠢的，也许是
Something expressed perhaps most dramatically and stupidly by
演员 Jon Voight的这段视频， Trump 本人在周三转发了此视频
the actor Jon Voight, in this video that Trump himself retweeted on Wednesday.
我的同胞们，今日我站于此
My fellow Americans, I stand here
和我所感受到的一起，对此谎言感到厌恶：
with all that feel as I do, disgusted with this lie.
Biden 成功了
That Biden has been chosen.
好像我们都不知道真相一样
As if we all don't know the truth.
这是自南北战争以来，我们最大的一次战斗
This is now our greatest fight since the Civil War.
正义与撒但的战争，是的，撒旦
The battle of righteousness versus Satan. Yes, Satan.
让我们战斗这场战斗，好像这是我们在地球上的最后一场战斗一样
Let us fight this fight as if it is our last fight on earth.
正如 Muhammad Ali （拳王）所说，
As Muhammad Ali said,
“还没有结束，直到你出了最后一拳”
"It's not over, till the last punch you have."
好的，这里面太值得说了
Okay. There's a lot there.
从着重强调左派是“撒旦”，到说
From doubling down on calling the left "Satan," to saying,
“我站在这里”，而他明明就坐着 （😂）
“I stand here”, when he's clearly sitting,
到引用 Muhammad Ali 的话，这句我们找不到证据说他说了的话
to that Muhammad Ali quote which we could not find any record of him saying.
这符合逻辑，因为听起来真不像 Muhammad Ali 说的话
Which does make sense，because it doesn't really sound like Muhammad Ali.
它没有修辞上，像"飞如蝶，刺如蜂"这样的识别度
It doesn't have the rhetorical flair of "Float like a butterfly, sting like a bee"
或者是带有“我攻击力如此之强，让药物都被会病倒”一般的智慧
Or the wit of "I'm so mean, I make medicine sick"
“直到你出了最后一拳”听起来不像 Muhammad Ali 说的，
"It's not over till last punch you have" sounds less like Muhammad Ali
更像是贴在《洛基4》盗版录像带上的广告语
and more like a blurb on a bootleg VHS cover of Rocky IV.
当然，那是一个荒谬的视频，
And sure, that's a ridiculous video,
但事实是，很多人相信这样的东西
but the fact is, a lot of people believe stuff like that.
当你不断坚持在大城市中选举被操控
And when you continually insist that the election was stolen in big cities and
并建议采取补救措施，呼吁内战以来最大的战斗，
suggest that remedying this, calls for the biggest fight since the Civil War,
事情开始变得非常严重
things start to get deadly serious.
上星期四，两名武装人员在费城会展中心外面被捕
Last Thursday, two armed men were arrested outside a Philadelphia convention center
在警察收到关于投票站的威胁情报后，
after police had received a tip about a threat to the vote-counting site.
一个负责唱票的城市专员之一
And one of the city commissioners in charge of ballot-counting,
顺便说一句，是共和党人，
a Republican, by the way, .
可以理解的，被吞噬了他办公室的混乱而吓到了
has been understandably rattled by the chaos engulfing his office
从内向外看，感觉一切都很混乱
From the inside-looking out, it feels all very deranged.
人们指责我们不会唱“那些”选票或者
It's people making accusations that we wouldn't count "those" votes or
人们在增加欺诈性选票，或，
people are adding fraudulent votes or
嗯，各种想象的疯狂的东西
um, just coming up with, just all sorts of crazy stuff.
诸如“你在作弊”之类的指控
Accusations like, You are cheating.
是
Yes.
“你正在操纵投票 ”
You are manipulating the vote.
是，或给我们办公室打电话，提醒我们...
Yes. Or calls to our offices, reminding us that, um...
这就是第二修正案（持枪权）的目的，就是为了对付我们这样的人
"This is what the Second Amendment is for, people like" us.
-你接到这样的电话吗？ -是
-You're getting calls like that?  -Yes.
那不是一个很隐晦的死亡威胁
That's a not-so-veiled death threat.
是，就因为我们唱票，
Yes. For counting votes. In a democracy.
太糟糕了
That's awful.
Trump 在这里玩的游戏很危险
And Trump is playing a dangerous game here.
因为“不是我的总统”和“不是总统”两者之间存在巨大差异
Because there is a huge difference between "Not my president" and "Not the president."
而且说清楚的事，那些如此愤怒的人，不是在一个真空环境中自己生闷气
And to be clear, people who are that angry are not riling themselves up in a vacuum.
他们持续不断地被给予错误信息，胡说八道的欺诈主张
They've been fed a steady diet of misinformation, bullshit fraud claims
以及诸如来自 Fox News, NewsMax, OAN 以受害者角度的讲述
and a victim narrative from outlets like Fox News, NewsMax, OAN
最重要的是， Trump 本人，本周的推文
And most importantly, Trump himself, Who's Twitter feed this week
穿梭于 Breitbart 的文章和宣称他赢了 Pennsylvania 州之间
oscillated between Breitbart articles, nonsense claims that he won Pennsylvania
以及一篇给Scott Baio（演员）很长的答复，你可能知道他因为
and one long reply to Scott Baio, who you might know
《欢乐时光》或《天才宝贝：宝贝天才2》
from Happy Days or from Superbabies Baby Geniuses 2
在那里，他和 Jon Voight 一起出演了
Where he starred alongside none other than Jon Voight.
我敢打赌，他们在现场玩得很开心，因为我保证，
I bet they had a lot of fun on set, because I guarantee,
没有其他人任何人开心
no one else did.
令人发指的是，Trump 选择在选举期间播种所有这些混乱局面，
And infuriatingly, Trump has chosen to sow all this chaos around the election,
尽管事实上，他知道事情已经结束了
despite the fact that deep down, he knows it's over.
星期五下午，最后一个州的结果尘埃落定
Friday afternoon, the final states were called by most outlets,
Joe Biden 以306票赢了 Trump 的232票
putting Joe Biden at 306 electoral votes, to Trump's 232.
就在那几个小时后， Trump 举行的新闻发布会上，
And during a press conference Trump held, just a few hours later,
他几乎承认了现实
he nearly acknowledged reality.
理想情况下，我们不会锁城，我不会，
Ideally, we won't go to a lockdown. I will not go
这届政府不会宣布封城
This administration will not be going to a lockdown.
希望，呃... 不管之后发生什么
Hopefully the, the, uh... whatever happens in the future,
谁知道哪个政府会上台
who knows which administration it will be,
我想时间会证明一切，但是...呃，我可以告诉你，
I guess time will tell, but... uh, I can tell you,
这届政府不会宣布封城
this administration will not go to a lockdown.
除非不会，时间不会证明，时间已经证明了！
Except no, time will not tell, time has told!
Trump 输掉了这次选举，他知道这一点
Trump lost this election and he knows it.
然而，在那次新闻发布会之后一个小时，
And yet, just an hour after that press conference,
他再次转发了选民欺诈的阴谋论
he was retweeting voter fraud conspiracies again.
这是可悲的，危险的，和从多层面来说
Which is pathetic, dangerous and many ways,
对一个总统来说非常“合适”的方式来导致许多人丧生
an appropriate code to a presidency that has destroyed so many lives.
不仅是他攻击的那些人，也有
Not only, of those that he's attacked, but also,
他声称要保护的那些人
of those he's claimed to protect.
我们很多人失去了亲人
So many of us have lost loved ones.
要么是因为你不能再爱他们，
Either because you can no longer square your love for them
因为他们对他（Trump）的爱
with their love for him.
或者是因为他们掉下了一个令人大脑坍塌的兔子洞
Or because they fell down a mind-melting rabbit hole
洞里装满了 Trump 非常乐于保持的阴谋论
of conspiracy theories that he happily perpetuated.
或者，因为他让致命的病毒肆虐，它tmd杀死了他们！
Or, because he let a deadly virus run wild and it fucking killed them!
现在，作为送给国家的礼物，
And now, as a parting gift to the country,
Trump 还能以某种方式使我们进一步分裂，
Trump is somehow managing to divide us even further,
同时还在最糟糕的时间，阻碍了他的继任者
while also hobbling his successor at the worst possible time.
这是绝对不可原谅的
Which is absolutely unforgiveable.
是的， Trump 明年不再担任总统的事实是件好事
And yes, the fact that Trump won't be president next year is good.
真的很棒！
It's really good!
但是还有很多工作要做，至少在短期内，
But there is a lot of work to do and at least in the short term,
事情会变得非常糟糕
things are going to suck for a while.
但是我们必须尝试修复这种伤害
But we have to try and repair this damage.
实际上，正如一位伟大的战士曾经说过的
In fact, as a great fighter once said
"还没有结束，直到你出了最后一拳""
"It's not over till the final fisting you give"
好吧，我不知道了，类似于这样的狗便便
Well, I don't know, some shit like that.
我不记得了
I don't remember anymore.
时间轴/不想校对/翻译/压制 by Pepita_貘饕_，禁止转载